

CONTACT

- www.giftegwuenu.com
- Haarlem, Netherlands

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: COMPUTER SCIENCE

2015

Houdegbe North American University Cotonou, BN

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue, React, Webpack, GraphQL, Jamstack, Node.js, SQL, Gridsome, Technical Writing, Adobe XD

SOCIAL



@lauragift



GIFT EGWUENU

Frontend Developer & Content Creator

ABOUT

Gift Egwuenu is a front-end developer passionate about making the web accessible to everyone and advocating building open and inclusive developer communities. She loves sharing her knowledge and does that through content creation on her blog and YouTube channel. She's a Media Developer Expert at Cloudinary, Microsoft MVP, an AuthO Ambassador, and a Nuxt.js Ambassador.

EXPERIENCE

CONTENT CREATOR

Gift Egwuenu| Feb 2018 - Present

• Creating helpful tech content on my personal blog and YouTube Channel that is beneficial to the community.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER CONSULTANT

Passionate People | August 2020 - Present

- Working with a client to help improve the developer experience by setting up CI/CD Enablement and a Content Management System.
- Building a conference hosting platform for one of the largest tech conferences in the Netherlands.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER & DEVELOPER EVANGELIST

Datopian | March 2020 - June 2020

- Designed and developed client facing user interfaces.
- Communicated with clients and designed UI mockups.
- Worked closely and interacted with the Frictionless Data Community via (chats, remote hangouts, and in-person events)
- Wrote documentation, guides and blog posts for Frictionless Data

CONTENT STRATEGIST

Ruby Together | Mar 2020 - Present

 Responsible for writing and publishing monthly updates to RubyGems Blog.
Maintaining existing documentation and writing new guides (RubyGems/Bundler docs).

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Andela | Aug 2018 - Mar 2020

- Responsible for building and deploying interactive web application using front end technologies.
- Collaborate excellently with peers and stakeholders in fast-paced distributed team.

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR

Rekkur Solutions | Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

- Worked with a diverse and remote team to help build features for a Hugo Custom Theme.
- Created relevant issues and fixes for Hugo based Theme (Syna)